<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shelby Bachman</title>
    <link>https://shelbybachman.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Shelby Bachman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Shelby Bachman</copyright><atom:link href="https://shelbybachman.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://shelbybachman.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shelbybachman.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m a Research Scientist at VivoSense, where I use data from wearable devices to develop digital measures that can be deployed in clinical trials. Prior to working at VivoSense, I completed my PhD in the Emotion &amp;amp; Cognition Lab at the University of Southern California, where I studied how stress and physiological arousal affect what we remember and pay attention to, and how these processes change across the lifespan. Prior to that, I studied neuroscience at Humboldt Universität zu Berlin and the University of Southern California.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>portfolio</title>
      <link>https://shelbybachman.github.io/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shelbybachman.github.io/portfolio/</guid>
      <description>Academic projects Isometric handgrip exercise speeds working memory responses in younger and older adults.
Decades of animal and pharmacological research have linked the brain&amp;rsquo;s noradrenergic system to working memory, but there has been relatively little non-pharmacological work in humans examining how isolated fluctuations in noradrenegic activity to working memory performance. We examined how performing isometric handgrip exercise, a manipulation known to influence noradrenergic activity, affected working memory performance. Our results indicated that performing handgrip decreased reaction times on a subsequent working memory task in both younger and older adults.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
